National Council On Household Employment Records 5226
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
- Series III. Conference(s) - on employee-employer relationshiops in the home, 1928 and 1931 (and others)
  - Sub-Series B. Conference Documents
    - Lists of organizations & individuals interested in receiving findings of National Conference, 1931 (Box 2, Folder 35)
    - Members of the National Committee, 1928 (Box 2, Folder 36)
    - Minutes of meetings, 1928-1931 (Box 2, Folder 37)
      Minutes of the National Committee on Employer-Employee Relationships in the Home. Includes agendas, minutes, & notes of meetings
    - Miscellaneous (Box 2, Folder 38)
      Includes miscellaneous items - study outline, handwritten notes, list, etc; not dated
    - Miscellaneous "not used" material, 1931 (Box 2, Folder 39)
      Includes questionnaire & article by Eva Von Baur Hansl "Household Occupations & the Employment Situation," 4p.
    - National Committee - Functions, 1928 (Box 2, Folder 40)
      3 p., "Functions of the National Committee on Employer-Employee Relationships in the Home" as formulated by the National Conference
    - National Committee - Misc, 1928-1931 (Box 2, Folder 41)
      4 pp. summary & information re the National Committee & misc
    - Problems/suggestions submitted to l928 Conference, 1928 (Box 2, Folder 42)
      Correspondence & lists of problems and suggestions by various groups & individuals for discussion at Conference
    - Programs, 1928-1931 (Box 2, Folder 43)
      Includes programs, drafts of programs, tentative programs of the Conferences
    - Publicity, 1928-1931 (Box 2, Folder 44)
      Clippings, correspondence re articles, mss. by Eva Von Baur Hansl, "Domesticity Dignified" & misc
    - Questionnaires (Box 2, Folder 45)
      miscellaneous questionnaires re domestic work, etc; not dated
    - Release, 1928 (Box 2, Folder 46)
      3 p. release, October l7, l928 re the 2 day conference
    - Reports, 1928-1931 (Box 2, Folder 47)
      Includes 5 p. report by Amey Watson entitled, "Progress & Problems in the Field Employer-Employee Relationships in the Home", & other misc. reports
    - Reports of the Findings Committee, 1928-1931 (Box 2, Folder 48)
      Includes reports of the Committee for both l928 & l93l Conferences
    - Standards, 1931 (Box 2, Folder 49)
      Household Workers re suggested standards for houseworkers
    - Summary - Conference - Watson, 1928 (Box 2, Folder 50)
      3 p. summary of l928 Conference re "Of Underlying Assumptions & Objectives of the Conference."
    - Summary - Conference, 1931 (Box 2, Folder 51)
      "Summary of 2nd Conference, April 13-l4, l93l," l9 pp.
    - Summary of Problems Submitted For Conference, 1928 (Box 2, Folder 52)
    - Summary of Work of Organizations, 1928 (Box 2, Folder 53)
      6 p. "Summary of Work Organizations" by Conference on Employer-Employee Relationships in the Home.
    - "Other Conferences", 1933 (Box 2, Folder 54)
      re Conference on Household Problems, Teachers College, May l7, l933; Conference on a Code of Household Employment, October l6, l933; & misc
    - "Other Conferences", 1937 (Box 2, Folder 55-56)
      "All-day Regional Conference on Household Employment, April 27, l937 at the NY Herald Tribune Institute." Includes programs, correspondence, notes, lists of attendees, case studies & misc
- Series IV. Subject Files
  - Apprenticeship - Household Employment - Mss. Notes, 1917-1921 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Bibliographies on Household Employment (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Britain Labor Party, 1932 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - California - Applications for Employment, 1931-1932 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - California - Assembly Bill 794 - Hours of Work/Household Employees (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - California - Division of Labor Statistics, 1940-1941 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - California - General, 1941 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - California, Los Angeles - Frank Wiggins Trade School, 1940-1941 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - California, Los Angeles, 1940-1941 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - California, Los Angeles - Training Course in Household Employment, 1942 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - California, San Diego, 1940 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - California, San Francisco, 1940-1941 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - California, Standards (Box 3, Folder 13)
    not dated
  - Canada. Home Service Training Schools (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Canada, Ontario Dept. of Labor, 1939 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Canada, Toronto - YWCA Notes, 1934 (Box 3, Folder 16)
    Jun-34
  - Census Data - Household Employment, 1937 (Box 3, Folder 17)
    17-Jun-37
  - Code of Ethics for Household Employees (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Colorado, Denver - Emily Griffith Opportunity School, 1935-1938 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Committee on Street Corner Markets for Household Workers in New York City, 1941 (Box 3, Folder 20)
    Minutes of the Sub-Committee, 8/20/4l
  - Committee on Supervised Homemaker - Housekeeper Service, National Conference on Social Work, 1939-1940 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Community Councils on Household Employment (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Contracts (Box 3, Folder 23)
    Sample - between mistress and maid; not dated
  - Cost of Living Surveys, 1937-1938 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Denmark, 1906-1931 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Detroit (Box 3, Folder 26)
    Household Employment Committee - Rules, standards, etc; not dated
  - Domestic Placement - Study, tests, etc., 1933-1934 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Domestic Workers Association, 1940-1941 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Domestic Workers - Germany, 1934 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Domestic Workers - Miscellaneous (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Domestic Workers - Photographs (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Domestic Workers - Social Insurance Research Project, 1939 (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - Domestic Workers Union - Organizing Literature, 1937 (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - Georgia (Atlanta) Community Employment Service Training School, Outline, 1930-1935 (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - Home Economics Depts. (State and Local), 1934-1935 (Box 3, Folder 35)
    Requests for material on household employment
  - Household Accidents - Student papers, 1936 (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - Household Employees, Attempts at Unionization, 1942-1943 (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - Household Employers' Council - First Household Employment Institute, Detroit (Box 3, Folder 38)
  - Household Employment - Application for test, handwritten notes, etc. (Box 3, Folder 39)
  - Household Employment - Employer questionnaire (Box 3, Folder 40)
  - Household Employment - High School Students (Box 3, Folder 41)
  - Household Employment - Household Employee Committee (St. Paul, Minneapolis) (Box 3, Folder 42)
  - Household Employment Institute (Colombia University) (Box 3, Folder 43)
  - Household Employment Legislation, 1939-1940 (Box 3, Folder 44)
  - Household Employment, 1933-1934 (Box 3, Folder 45-47)
    Mss. and typescript tests designed to test potential confidence of servants
  - Household Employment - Notes on a course (Box 3, Folder 48)
  - Household Employment - Pennsylvania, 1933-1939 (Box 3, Folder 49)
  - Household Employment - Personnel problems (Box 3, Folder 50)
  - Household Employment Play (Box 3, Folder 51)
    misc.
  - Household Employment Play, 1939 (Box 3, Folder 52)
    Norma Goodfriend, "Afternoon Bridge on Wednesday" and "Household Helpers Day Off," January l2, l939
  - Household Employment Play (Box 3, Folder 53)
    Wainwright, Helen, "Give and Take", not dated
  - Household Employment, 1934-1935 (Box 3, Folder 54)
    Requests for Material from Emergency Relief Administration (State and Local)
  - Household Employment - St. Louis, 1935 (Box 3, Folder 55)
  - Household Employment Symposium Program, 1939 (Box 3, Folder 56)
  - Household Employment Tests, Questionnaires, etc. (Box 3, Folder 57)
  - Household Employment Training (Box 3, Folder 58)
  - Household Employment Training Course (Box 3, Folder 59)
  - Household Employment Training Project (Box 3, Folder 60)
  - Household Employment - Washington State (Box 3, Folder 61)
  - Household Employment - Wisconsin, 1939 (Box 3, Folder 62)
  - Household Time Record, 1924 (Box 3, Folder 63)
  - Household Training (Box 3, Folder 64)
    List of Schools offering training under George-Dean, Smith Hughes Act, not dated
  - Household Workers Training Project, 1938 (Box 3, Folder 65)
  - Institute on Labor Relationships Within the Home (Box 3, Folder 66)
  - National Youth Administration, 1941-1951 (Box 3, Folder 67)
  - New York Household Placement Association (Box 3, Folder 68)
  - New York Roslyn High School - Household Training in Domestic Service (Box 3, Folder 69)
  - New York State - Household Employment, 1939 (Box 3, Folder 70)
  - Oklahoma - Household Employment, 1940-1942 (Box 3, Folder 71)
  - Pennsylvania - Medical Society Health Examination form (Box 3, Folder 72)
  - Pennsylvania (Philadelphia) Central Committee on Household Occupations (Box 3, Folder 73)
    Questionnaires on Domestic Employment and on Household Employment
  - Pennsylvania (Philadelphia) Council on Household Occupations, 1931 (Box 3, Folder 74)
    minutes, correspondence
  - Pennsylvania (Philadelphia) Institute on Household Occupations, 1937-1941 (Box 3, Folder 75)
  - Pennsylvania (Philadelphia) YMCA, 1945 (Box 3, Folder 76)
    Standards for Household Employment presented by Sub-Committee on Household Employment
  - Philadelphia Committee on Household Employment, 1929 (Box 3, Folder 77)
    The Job Analysis of Household Maintenance - Report of the Committee, l929 (?) unpaged
  - Pittsburgh Committee on Household Employment, 1937 (Box 3, Folder 78)
    Proposals for a voluntary agreement in household employment
  - Puerto Rico - Household Employees, 1938 (Box 3, Folder 79)
  - Schedules for Household Employees (Box 3, Folder 80)
  - Servant Problem, 1925 (Box 3, Folder 81)
    Excerpts from the "Psychology of the Servant Problem"
  - Servants (Box 3, Folder 82)
  - Unemployment Compensation - Legislation, 1939 (Box 3, Folder 83)
  - WPA Household Demonstration Project, 1938 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    Philadelphia Standards Committee - Proposals for a Voluntary Agreement in Household Employment
  - WPA for Pennsylvania. Household Workers Training Project, 1938-1939 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - WPA for Pennsylvania. Household Workers Training Project, 1938-1940 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    reports and forms
  - WPA for Pennsylvania. Household Service Demonstration Project, 1938 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    Semi-Annual Report, June 30, l938
  - WPA - Household Workers Project, 1934-1939 (Box 4, Folder 5-6)
  - World's YWCA - Misc, 1930-1940 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - YWCA - Evaluation of Household Employment & sample questionnaires, 1929 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - YWCA Hartford. Standards for Household Employment (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - YWCA Industrial Department, 1933 (Box 4, Folder 10)
    tentative standards adopted by household employees, 4/7/33
  - YWCA Philadephia, Pennsylvania - Household Institute Project, 1936-1937 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - YWCA Public Affairs Committee, 1939 (Box 4, Folder 12)
    statement on extension of social security to domestic workers, 3/22/39
  - YWCA. Trade School (NYC) - School of Household Employment, 1895-1933 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - MISCELLANEOUS (Box 4, Folder 14)
- Series V. Publications and Miscellaneous Manuscripts
  - Alameda County Committee on Household Employment for Girls (Box 4, Folder 15)
    General Standards of Household Employment for the Girl Under Twenty-One Who Lives In Her Employer's Home. Oakland Public Schools, n.d. 3 p
  - All in the Family: A Good Way For Women to Reform Industry Is to Start With The Industry of Home-Making, 1928 (Box 4, Folder 16)
    Womans Press, February l928. pp. 82-85
  - American Association for Labor Legislation., 1930 (Box 4, Folder 17)
    Employment Agencies Officially Exposed. Sworn Testimony Shows Urgent Need of State Action. Substance of Voluminous Unpublished Proceedings. New York Sate. Industrial Commission. l0 p.
  - Anderson, Mary. "An Occupational Analysis of Household Employment.", 1938 (Box 4, Folder 18)
    Reprinted from Seventh International Management Congress. Washington, D.C. Homes Management Section. 7 p.
  - "Household Employment." (Box 4, Folder 19)
    Reprint #37. Chicago, Social Science Associates, not dated, 4 p.
  - Social Security for Household Employees, 1939 (Box 4, Folder 20)
    U.S. Department of Labor, Women's Bureau, Washington, D.C. May l3, l939. (Radio Talk Over Station W.J.S.V.) 4 p
  - Andrews, Benjamin R. "Household Employment and Community Resources.", 1938 (Box 4, Folder 21)
    Reprinted from Seventh International Management Congress. Washington, D.C. Home Management Section. pp. 6la-6lc
  - "Household Employment: Its Background and Prospects.", 1931 (Box 4, Folder 22)
    Reprinted from the Women's Press, July l93l. 4 p
  - "New York Symposium on Household Employment.", 1940 (Box 4, Folder 23)
    Journal of Home Economics, February l940. pp. 98-99 & l36.
  - Bartlett, Helen. Maid Service for the Average Household (Box 4, Folder 24)
    Chicago, The Chicago Tribune, not dated. 8 p
  - Belcher, Elizabeth C. Household Employment, 1940 (Box 4, Folder 25)
    63 p.
  - Beuter, Dorothy. The News Reel, 1939 (Box 4, Folder 26)
    Vol. XIV, April l939. League of Industrial Girls of the Chicago Y.W.C.A. Chicago, April l939. 20 p
  - Boone, Gladys. Household Employment-Lynchburg Study, 1936-1937 (Box 4, Folder 27)
    Y.W.C.A., Lynchburg, Virginia. 6 p
  - Brittain, W.M. "Advantages of the Port of Baltimore, U.S.A.", 1924 (Box 4, Folder 28)
    Reprinted from the Journal of Commerce of New York, March l5th, l924. l8 p.
  - Bromley, Dorothy Dunbar. "Are Servants People? (Box 4, Folder 29)
    Condensed from Scribner's Magazine. pp. 53-55
  - Brown, Jean. Brief on Household Employment in Relation to Trade Union Organization, 1938 (Box 4, Folder 30)
    Washington: U.S. Department of Labor, Women's Bureau. l7 p
  - Concerns of Household Workers. Program With Household Workers in the Y.M.C.A, 1941 (Box 4, Folder 31)
    New York, The Womans Press. l67 p
  - Domestic Workers and Unions, 1938 (Box 4, Folder 32)
    Reprint from American Federationist, May l938. l2 p. carbon
  - Household Workers, 1940 (Box 4, Folder 33)
    Washington: U.S. Department of Labor, Women's Bureau. 48 p
  - "Labor Relationships in the Home.", 1940 (Box 4, Folder 34)
    New York, The Womans Press, October l940. 2 p
  - The Negro Woman Worker, 1938 (Box 4, Folder 35)
    Bulletin No. l65. Washington: U.S. Department of Labor, Women's Bureau. l7 p.
  - S.O.S. for Social Security. A Memorandum Prepared for Household Employee Projects, 1941 (Box 4, Folder 36)
    Division of Community Y.W.C.A.'s. National Board, Y.W.C.A., New York. l3 p
  - "What Are Household Employers Going to Do?" Program Papers for Today and Tomorrow, 1941 (Box 4, Folder 37)
    New York, The Womans Press. l5 p
  - "What Our $7 a Week Won't Buy", 1941 (Box 4, Folder 38)
    Reprinted from the Woman Press Magazine, April l94l. 3 p
  - Brown, Julie Craighead. "Mistress and Maid Sit Down Together", 1942 (Box 4, Folder 39)
    A Report of a Community Conference on Household Employment. Forecast, February l942. pp. 35, 76-79
  - Bulletin of the Domestic Reform League, 1909 (Box 4, Folder 40)
    Vol. III, No. 3, April l909. 4 p. (Boston)
  - Handbook for Instructors of Part-Time and Evening Trade Extension Classes in Care of the House, 1940 (Box 4, Folder 41)
    Bureau of Industrial Teacher-Training, in cooperation with the State Department of Vocational Education, Austin, Texas 94p.
  - "A Butler's Life Story.", 1910 (Box 4, Folder 42)
    The Independent, (July l9l0). pp. 77-82
  - Byrne, Harriet A. & Cecile Hillyer. Unattached Women on Relief in Chicago, 1937, 1938 (Box 4, Folder 43)
    Bulletin No. l58. Washington: U.S. Department of Labor. Women's Bureau. 84 p
  - Canada-Department of Labour. Training for Household Employment, 1940 (Box 4, Folder 44)
    Dominion-Provincial Youth Training Programme. Department of Labour, Ottawa, May l940. 5 p
  - Carr, Dolly. "Help Wanted", 1940 (Box 4, Folder 45)
    Baby Talk, Vol. V, No. ll. New York, November l940. p. l3, 30-32
  - Cheyney, Alice S. "Cinderella and the Law in Europe", 1938 (Box 4, Folder 46)
    New York, The Womans Press, May l938. 3 p
  - Chicago Girl, 1930 (Box 4, Folder 47)
    Vol. 2, #l, January l930
  - Cline, Doris A. Report on S.E.R.A. Project 82 (Box 4, Folder 48)
    F I T A. Bulletin No. 22, Department of Guidance and Placement, Detroit Public Schools, Detroit, Michigan. File No. 6502, no date. 20 p
  - Colwell, Irene. Report on the Community Employment Service Training School for Colored Servants, 1934 (Box 4, Folder 49)
    Atlanta, Georgia, June l934. 8 p
  - Health Tests for Household Workers (Box 4, Folder 50)
    Committee on Health Tests for Household Workers, 4 p. not dated
  - Employer-Employee Co-operation in the Home, 1937 (Box 4, Folder 51)
    Committee on Household Employment. Council of Social Agencies. Family Division. Rochester, l937. l0 p
  - Suggested Standards for Employment - General House Worker, 1940 (Box 4, Folder 52)
    Committee on Labor and Industry. New York, Women's City Club of New York, January, l940. 4 p
  - Solving the Servant Problem (Box 4, Folder 53)
    Community Employment Service Training School. Atlanta, 3p. No date
  - Household Employment in Hartford, Waterbury and Litchfield, Connecticut, 1936 (Box 4, Folder 54)
    Connecticut Department of Labor in Cooperation With the Y.W.C.A. of Hartford. Hartford, Connecticut. May 1936. 41 p.
  - Colored Women as Industrial Workers in Philadelphia, 1919-1920 (Box 4, Folder 55)
    Consumers League of Eastern Pennsylvania. Philadelphia, 47p
  - Cook, Cara. Help Wanted!, 1939 (Box 4, Folder 56)
    New York, Women's Trade Union League. 24 p
  - Cornell, Marie. Standards of Placement Agencies for Household Employees, 1934 (Box 4, Folder 57)
    U.S. Department of Labor, Women's Bureau. Bulletin. No. ll2. Washington, G.P.O. 68 p
  - Crafts, Mabel E. "Personnel and General Character Traits Important in Service Occupations.", 1934 (Box 4, Folder 58)
    9p
  - "Placement Follow-Up of Women.", 1933 (Box 4, Folder 59)
    Reprinted from the Personnel Journal, Vol. XI, No. 5, February l933. 12 p
  - Racial Relations in Domestic Service, 1932 (Box 4, Folder 60)
    5p
  - Analysis of Cancelled Orders, 1931 (Box 4, Folder 61)
    Service Section. Supplemental Report to Progress Report. Public Employment Center of Rochester. Rochester, NY. December 3l, l93l. 6 p
  - Davenport, Winifred A. "Can Women Solve the Servant Problem.", 1931 (Box 4, Folder 62)
    The Forecast, June l93l. pp. 343-344, 373. 3 p
  - District of Columbia Works Progress Administration. Household Service Project (Box 4, Folder 63)
    Household Service Project #332, no date. 3 p
  - Training for Service (Box 4, Folder 64)
    3p, no date
  - "Do Servants Need A Code? A Socratic Dialogue.", 1934 (Box 4, Folder 65)
    The Forum and Century. Vol. XCII, No. l, pp. 34-4l. New York, The Forum Publishing Co., Inc., July l934. 8 p
  - Domestic Bureau, Some Suggestions for Employers and Employees (Box 4, Folder 66)
    Domestic Bureau, Central Office for Refugees. London. No date, 23 p
  - "Would You Tolerate Domestic Slavery? Is There Such a Thing As Domestic Slavery Today?" (Box 4, Folder 67)
    Domestic Employees Club, Inc. Milwaukee, Wisconsin. No date. 4p
  - Domestic Worker's Guild, Hamstead and Area. First Annual Report, 1932-1933 (Box 4, Folder 68)
    England, 7 p
  - Dummer,Mrs. W.F. The Responsibility of the Home, 1921 (Box 4, Folder 69)
    Read at the Conference on Social Hygiene Education, Los Angeles, California, April 192l. 8 p
  - Emery, Ruby Nance. Detailed Unit Plans For A Course in Household Service, 1938 (Box 4, Folder 70)
    Kansas State College, Department of Education. Summer, l938. 42 p.
  - Detailed Unit Plans For A Course in Household Service, 1938 (Box 4, Folder 71)
    Kansas State College, Department of Education. Summer, l938. 56 p
  - Fisher, Katharine. Training the Homemaker's Helper, 1939 (Box 4, Folder 72)
    New York, Good Housekeeping Institute, 23p
  - Food Trades Department. Training Program for Household Service, 1939 (Box 4, Folder 73)
    Bulletin No. 92. January, l939. 20 p
  - Training Program for Household Service, 1940 (Box 4, Folder 74)
    Los Angeles, California. May l940. 22 p
  - "For the Preservation of the American Home" (Box 4, Folder 75)
    New York, Scientific Housekeeping, Inc., no date. 8 p
  - Fox, Grace. "Woman Domestic Workers in Washington, D.C., l940.", 1942 (Box 4, Folder 76)
    Monthly Labor Review, February l942. 22 p
  - Frankel, Ruth L. "Is Homemaking a Profession?", 1931 (Box 4, Folder 77)
    Practical Home Economics, Vol. IX, Dec. l93l, No. 2. pp. 369, 384.
  - "Training for Domestic Service", 1940 (Box 4, Folder 78)
    Forecast for Home Economists, Vol. LVI, No. 9, November l940. pp. 534-535, 552, 554, 556, 564. 7 p
  - "When We Consider the Servant Problem - From the Point of the Housewife", 1930 (Box 4, Folder 79)
    The Forecast, Vol. XL, Number 3, September l930. pp. 134, l77-l78. 3 p
  - Fredericks, Christine. Household Engineering: Scientific Management in the Home, 1923 (Box 4, Folder 80)
    18p
  - Gordon, Allison. What Shall We Do About Household Employment?, 1940 (Box 4, Folder 81)
    American Association of University Women. Washington, D.C., October, l940. 45 p
  - Greene, Lorenzo J. and Myra Colson Callis. The Employment of Negros in the District of Columbia (Box 4, Folder 82)
    The Association for the Study of Negro Life and History, Inc. Washington, D.C., no date., 89 p
  - Hackett, Catherine. "A Code for Housewives.", 1934 (Box 4, Folder 83)
    The Forum & Century. April l934, Vol. XCI, No. 4. pp. 238-242
  - Hale, Beatrice Forbes-Robertson. "The Future of Marriage As Forecast.", 1931 (Box 4, Folder 84)
    The Forecast, June l93l. pp. 333, 372, 384. 3 p
  - Haynes, Elizabeth Ross, A.M. "Negroes in Domestic Service in the United States", 1923 (Box 4, Folder 85)
    Reprinted from the Journal of Negro History, Vol. VIII, No. 4, October l923. Washington, D.C.: The American Association for the Study of Negro Life & History, Inc. pp. 384-442
  - Holmes, Henry W. "Homemaking and the Personal Equation", 1929 (Box 4, Folder 86)
    Journal of Home Economics, Vol. 2l, No. ll, November l929. pp. 797-808
  - Hope, Edward. "To Whom It May Concern", 1941 (Box 4, Folder 87)
    Saturday Evening Post, November l94l. 4 p
  - Horkheimer, Mary Foley and John W. Diffor, M.A. Educators Guide to Free Films, 1946 (Box 4, Folder 88)
    Sixth Edition. Randolph, Wisconsin: Educators Progress Service. 303 p
  - Household Employees News, 1941 (Box 4, Folder 89)
    Vol. l, #3, November l94l and Vol. l, #4, December l94l
  - Household Employment - A Symposium. (3 articles), 1939 (Box 4, Folder 90)
    Ellen Woodward. "W.P.A.'s Program of Training for Housework", pp. 86-88; Amey E. Watson. "The Responsibility of the Home Economist for Improving Employer-Employee Relationships in the Home". pp. 88-90; Leila Doman. "Legislation in the Field of Houshehold Employment." pp. 90-95. Journal of Home Economics, February l939, Vol. 3l, No. 2. Washington, D.C
  - Household Employment Conference, 1941 (Box 4, Folder 91)
    Held at Young Women's Christian Association, Oklahoma City, Oklahoma, May 6, l94l. 29 p
  - Household Employment in Seattle, 1937 (Box 4, Folder 92)
    King County, Washington: Advisory Committee on Social Security to the Board of County Commissioners. September l937. 8l p
  - Training for Service (Box 4, Folder 93)
    Household Service Demonstration Centers. Works Progress Administration. Washington, D.C., no date. 3 p
  - Humeston, Caroline. "Household Can Be Fun"., 1940 (Box 4, Folder 94)
    Reprinted from Occupations, the Vocational Guidance Magazine, February, l940. New York: National Vocational Guidance Association. 4 p
  - Hurst, Marion. Household Employees Handbook, 1939 (Box 4, Folder 95)